[{"question": "If a man betrothes a woman with a false condition, is the betrothal valid?",
"answer": "If he misled her to her advantage by giving her something of greater value than he claimed she is betrothed.",
"source": "Kiddushin 2:2"},
{"question":"Can a man be alone with two women if his wife is there?",
"answer":"Yes, a man can be alone with two women if his wife is in the house. He can even sleep in a room with two women if his wife is there.",
"source":"Kiddushin 4:12"},
{"question":"If one brother performs yibum with the widow of his late brother and then another brother is born, is the widow of the original brother considered an ervah to the youngest in case the second brother dies?",
"answer":"No, she is only an ervah if he is born while she is waiting for yibum.  In that moment, she is prohibited, but not after. He can perform yibum or she needs chalitzah.",
"source":"Yevamot 2:2"},
{"question":"Must a man perform chalitzah with two sisters who fall to him for yibum?",
"answer":"No, there is no yibum bond between them since they would be ervahs to the one remaining brother.",
"source":"Yevamot 3:4"},
{"question":"If a woman falls to two married brothers for yibum and one of them performs maamar before dying, can the last brother perform yibum?",
"answer":"He may choose one to perform yibum and must do chalitzah to the other. This is because maamar is either a full marriage or not at all.",
"source":"Yevamot 3:9"},

{"question":"If a daughter of a Kohen who is a widow becomes betrothed to the Kohen Gadol or if she is a divorcee or chalutzah and betrothes a regular Kohen, can she still eat terumah?", 
"answer":"Until the marriage is completed, they can eat terumah.", 
"source": "Yevamot 6:3"},

{"question":"Can the Kohen Gadol marry a bogeress?", 
"answer":"Yes, as long as she is still a technical virgin.",
"source": "Yevamot 6:4"},

{"question":"Can women converts from Egypt and Edom enter the congregation right away?",
"answer": "Yes, by a kol vachomer we see that if women from Ammon and Moab enter immediately while their men are eternally banned, those from Egypt and Edom have men banned only three generations.  Thus, they should all the moreso be permitted immediately.",
"source": "Yevamot 8:3"},

{"question": "What is the status of a Kohen who is an androgyne with both male and female organs?",
"answer":"He is as a male.  He can marry a woman who is permitted to eat terumah.",
"source": "Yevamot 8:6"},

{"question": "If a woman uses the testimony of a single witness that her husband died overseas and remarries, before learning that her original husband returned, can she do yibum if her first husband dies before divorcing her?",
"answer":"Yes, she may do yibum with her first husband's brother. Additionally, any child she has with the first husband after his return is not a mamzer, though their relationship is forbidden.",
"source": "Yevamot 10:1"},

{"question":"If a boy of nine years and one day cohabits with his yevamah, and then his brother of the same age cohabits with her, then what is the status of each relationship?",
"answer":"Neither is disqualified. Either the cohabitation is fully effective, in which case the second has no effect because the first was complete, or neither has any effect.",
"source":"Yevamot 10:7"},

{"question":"If a boy of nine years and one day cohabitrs with one yevamah and then with her cowife, what is the status of these relationships?",
"answer": "He is still eligible to the first one. His cohabitation is either fully binding or not at all.",
"source":"Yevamot 10:8"},

{"question":"What happens when a brother of nine years and one day does yibum with his yevamah, marries another woman as an adult, and dies childless, leaving one remaning brother?",
"answer":"The remaining brother can do yibum with one and then must do chalitzah with the other. They may both be married to him or only one is.  Two actions must be taken by the reamining brother.",
"source":"Yevamot 10:9"},

{"question":"Can chalitzah be valid if performed with fewer than three judges?",
"answer":"Yes, three judges is preferable but not essential.",
"source":"Yevamot 12:5"},

{"question":"If two cowives go overseas with a husband and the come back with a disagreement about how their husband died, one saying it was of natural causes and the other saying he was killed, can they both remmary and recieve their ketubah payment?",
"answer": "Since each agrees that he is dead, they can both remarry. ",
"source": "Yevamot 15:5"}
]